I mentioned before an AI company called vellum.
인공지능 회사인 베룸을 언급했었죠
When we were talking about the different questions, they had come up with that question about scales
다른 질문들에 대해 이야기할 때 파충류의 비늘에 대한 질문이
on reptiles that we asked GPT four zero and zero one preview vellum publishes a leaderboard, which
나왔는데요 GPT 400과 01 미리 보기 벨럼은 리더보드를 만들었습니다 나중에 다시
we will come back to in future weeks, but it has a lot of super interesting information that ranks
살펴보도록 하죠 다양한 llm의 순위와 비교를 하는 흥미로운 정보가 많이
and compares different llms.
있어요
And there are a bunch of different leaderboards that we'll look at when we talk about picking the right
당면한 작업에 맞는 LLM을 고르는 것에 대해 얘기할 때 다양한 leaderboard가
It's a good one to bookmark, but in particular, there's something useful on the vellum website, which
즐겨찾기에 좋고 특히 피지 웹사이트에 유용한 게 있어요 다른 곳에선
I don't think I find somewhere else that you can also download should you wish.
못 찾을 것 같은데 원하시면 다운로드도 가능해요
According to that pop up, and it's right here, about halfway up on the Valimai LLM leaderboard website,
팝업 창에 따르면 바로 여기 있네요 Valimai LLM leaderboard
and it's a table that compares the context windows with the costs of the different frontier models.
웹사이트의 중간쯤에 있어요 컨텍스트 창과 다른 프론티어 모델의 비용을 비교하는 테이블이죠
And it's really useful to have to hand, particularly when you're talking about costs.
직접 하는 게 정말 유용해요 특히 비용에 관해서요
First of all, let's just mention the context windows that we talked about.
먼저, 아까 얘기했던 컨텍스트 창을 언급하죠
So the model with the largest context window is Gemini 1.5 flash, and it has an outrageous context
문맥상 창문이 가장 큰 모델은 제미니 1호예요 5 플래시, 그리고 문맥상 충격적인 창문이 있어요
Outrageous.
말도 안 돼요
1 million tokens.
백만 토큰요
And you may remember a million tokens means for normal English language about 750,000 words, which
토큰 백만 개는 일반적인 영어에서 약 750,000단어의 뜻입니다 셰익스피어
isn't far off the complete works of Shakespeare.
작품과 크게 다르지 않죠
If you remember, I think we thought that was 1.2 million tokens, perhaps.
1편인 줄 알았던 것 같아요 2백만 토큰 정도요
So you could almost fit the complete works of Shakespeare in one prompt into Gemini to have it to continue
셰익스피어의 모든 작품을 제미니 1호에 끼워 맞출 수 있었죠
So that is extraordinarily wide context window.
5번 섬광이에요
The Claude series of models have a 200,000 token context window, and the GPT set have mostly 128,000
클로드 시리즈 모델은 200,000 토큰 컨텍스트 창을 가지고 있고 GPT는 대부분 128,000 토큰 컨텍스트 창을
token context window.
가지고 있네요
And again, remember that that means that the all of the series of prompts in one conversation, the
다시 한 번 기억하세요 하나의 대화에 모든 프롬프트, 대화 안의 입력 응답
input in a conversation, the response the next input, the response, and also the system prompt at
다음 입력, 응답 그리고 시작 부분에 있는 시스템도요
They all have to fit within that context window.
전부 그 문맥에 맞아야 해요
And actually also all of the tokens that get generated in the output, because each each token is generated
그리고 출력된 모든 토큰들도 마찬가지입니다 각각의 토큰은 한 번에 하나씩
one at a time and then passed in and it generates the next token given all of the input and output that
생성되어 전달되고 다음 토큰을 생성합니다 이전의 모든 입력과 출력 결과에
came before it.
의해서요
So that's what has to fit into the context window.
컨텍스트 창에 맞아야 해요
But there's a lot of space for that in 128,000 tokens.
하지만 128,000 토큰으로 만들기엔 공간이 너무 많아요
I guess it's what about about 100,000 words.
100,000단어 정도 되겠네요
So that's that's how to look at the context window size.
컨텍스트 창 크기를 보는 방법이었어요
And now over here we get a sense of the cost.
Get up! Get up! 이제 여기서 그 비용을 알 수 있죠
And at first blush you might think this doesn't exactly look like it's super cheap if you take something
얼핏 보면 저렴해 보이지 않을 수도 있습니다
like Claude 3.5 sonnet, which is the one that I frequently find myself using in the most powerful LLM
클로드 3 같은 경우라면요 지구상에서 가장 강력한 LLM에서 자주 사용하는 소네트 5편이죠
By most measures, you'll see that its cost is $3 per input token, $15 per output token.
입력 토큰 하나에 3달러 출력 토큰 하나에 15달러죠
It sounds quite expensive, but no, it's because it's not $3 per input token.
꽤나 비쌀 것 같지만 아닙니다 입력 토큰 당 3달러가 아니기 때문이죠
It's $3 per million input tokens, $3 per million input tokens.
백만당 3달러 입력 토큰 백만당 3달러 입력 토큰이죠
So if you passed in in your input prompt, the complete works of Shakespeare, then you'd be paying
입력 프롬프트에 셰익스피어 전집을 입력하면 3달러보다 조금 더 많은
a little bit more than $3.
비트를 내야 해요
So I just want to get across that whilst these numbers are meaningful and they are real numbers that
이 숫자들이 의미 있고 주의 깊게 봐야 할 실제 숫자일 때 대시보드를
one needs to watch for, and you can bring up the dashboard with each of these and monitor carefully
불러와서 API 비용을 조심스럽게 모니터링하세요.
Typically, the kinds of things we're going to be doing on this course are asking short business questions,
이 과정에서 저희가 주로 하는 건 숏 비즈니스 질문입니다
summarizing things, trying to draw quick conclusions.
요약하고 빠른 결론을 내리려고 하죠
You'll find that you will be costing less than a cent for most of them, less than than a fraction of
비용은 대부분 1센트 이하로 들 겁니다 1달러도 안 되는 비율로요
The model that we will use most often is GPT four mini, and that will cost us $0.15 per million input
주로 사용할 모델은 GPT 4 미니인데 비용은 0달러예요 입력 토큰 1500만 개와
tokens and $0.60 per million output tokens.
0달러예요 출력 토큰은 6천만 대 1이에요
And so, as you can imagine, you have to generate a fair amount of content in order to be able to scratch
상상하셨다시피 상당한 양의 콘텐츠를 생성해야 실제 가격의 표면을
the surface in terms of a real price, and bearing in mind that these are large models and a lot of
긁어낼 수 있습니다 이런 대형 모델들을 실행하고 결과의 품질을 전달하려면
compute is required to run these and be able to deliver the quality of results we get.
많은 컴퓨팅이 필요하다는 걸 염두에 두고요
These API costs do seem to me to be to be very reasonable in the circumstances.
API 비용은 제가 보기엔 아주 합리적인 것 같아요
So I hope this gives you some some, some clarity, some perspective on what these costs are like and
이 일을 계기로 좀 더 명확해졌으면 좋겠어요 비용이 얼마나 드는지 어떤 의미인지
what they mean.
말이죠
The total cost is then the sum of your cost for your input tokens by by this number, plus the cost
합계 비용은 입력 토큰에 대한 비용의 합을 이 숫자로 나눈 것입니다. 거기에 생성된 모든 출력
of any output tokens that got generated.
토큰의 비용을 더하죠.
And in the APIs you can specify a a maximum number of output tokens to generate to stop it from going
API에서 최대 출력 토큰의 수를 지정하여 생성하여 너무 멀리 가는 것을 막을
too far.
수 있죠
Uh, so that gives you a good sense of the costs.
그래서 비용이 어느 정도인지 알 수 있죠
And you should bookmark this page and have it as something that you come back to anytime that you want.
이 페이지를 즐겨찾기 해서 언제든 원할 때 다시 보도록 해두세요
A little bit more clarity on how to think about these costs.
비트에 대해 좀 더 명확하게 생각할 수 있죠
And as I say, the time when it really becomes meaningful is when you're building a system that's going
말씀드렸듯이 정말 의미있는 때는 모델에 천 개의 호출을 하는
to maybe make a thousand calls to the model, and then you have to really bear in mind, how are these
시스템을 구축할 때입니다 그러면 정말 염두에 두어야 합니다 이런 비용이 어떻게
costs going to add up?
증가할까요?